https://www.astronomyedinburgh.org/privacy-policy/

Skip to contentPrivacy Policy Privacy Policymark2020-11-02T16:18:02+00:00This privacy policy will explain how our organisation uses the personal data we collect from you when you use our website or join our Society.The Astronomical Society of Edinburgh is referred to as the Society.Topics:What data do we collect?How do we collect your data?How will we use your data?How do we store your data?MarketingWhat are your data protection rights?What are cookies?How do we use cookies?What types of cookies do we use?How to manage your cookiesPrivacy policies of other websitesChanges to our privacy policyHow to contact usHow to contact the appropriate authoritiesOur organisation collects the following data:Personal identification informationWe collect your name and email addressThe legal basis for processing your information is under ‘contract’ as the payment of your membership fee to the Society entitles you to take up the benefits of membership.You directly provide us with most of the data we collect. We collect data and process data when you:Apply to become a member of the SocietyContact us through our website contact formsCreate an account on the Members’ websiteUse or view our website via your browser’s cookiesHow will we use your data?We collect your data so that we can:Reply to your messagesEnable you to be part of the SocietyEnable you to access the Members’ websiteManage your Society membershipSend you newslettersKeep you updated on Society newsThe only time we share your data with other organisations is with HMRC if you have agreed to Gift Aid your subscription.Data retentionWe will only keep your data for the length of your membership or as required by HMRC. We will however, keep your name and length of membership for our historical archives.How do we store your data?We securely store your membership data in a secure, online locationOnline login and newsletter subscription details are stored securely in online encrypted databases.MarketingWe do not use your data for marketing purposes.What are your data protection rights?We would like to make sure you are fully aware of all of your data protection rights. Every user is entitled to the following:The right to access – You have the right to request copies of your personal data. We may charge you a small fee for this service.The right to rectification – You have the right to request that we correct any information you believe is inaccurate. You also have the right to request us to complete the information you believe is incomplete.The right to erasure – You have the right to request that we erase your personal data, under certain conditions.The right to restrict processing – You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.The right to object to processing – You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.The right to data portability – You have the right to request that we transfer the data that we have collected to another organisation, or directly to you, under certain conditions.You can modify your subscription to our email newsletter system at any time. Links will be displayed in all emails you receive.If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us.CookiesCookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behaviour information. When you visit our websites, we may collect information from you automatically through cookies or similar technologyFor further information, visit allaboutcookies.org.How do we use cookies?We use cookies in a range of ways to improve your experience on our website, including:Keeping you signed inUnderstanding how you use our websiteWhat types of cookies do we use?Our website uses:Functionality – we use these cookies so that we recognise you on our website and remember your previously selected preferences. These could include what language you prefer and location you are in. A mix of first-party and third-party cookies are used.How to manage cookiesYou can set your browser not to accept cookies, and the above website tells you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, in a few cases, some of our website features may not function as a result.Privacy policies of other websitesOur website contains links to other websites. Our privacy policy applies only to our website, so if you click on a link to another website, you should read their privacy policy.Changes to our privacy policyWe keep the privacy policy under regular review and place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on 2 November 2020How to contact usIf you have any questions about this privacy policy, the data we hold on you, or you would like to exercise one of your data protection rights, please do not hesitate to contact us.How to contact the appropriate authorityShould you wish to report a complaint or if you feel that we have not addressed your concern in a satisfactory manner, you may contact the Information Commissioner’s Office.The Information Commissioner’s Office – Scotland Queen Elizabeth House Sibbald Walk Edinburgh EH8 8FTTelephone: 0303 123 1115 Email: Scotland@ico.org.uk
This site uses cookies. Find out more in our Privacy Policy.Okay, thank you
Go to Top
